Guide to the Underground Comix collection, 1948-1978.
Underground Comix collection,
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Underground Comix collection, 1948-1978.
8644
Mark, Hime.
3.3 cubic feet.
Printed materials, publications.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
A collection of underground comic books and related printed material, spanning from approximately 1948-1978. The collection contains precursors to the genre, including 174 Tiajuana Bibles, individual zines, along with galley proofs and proof books of issues of Zap and Motor City. The collection also features an extensive representation of some of the genre's most celebrated titles such as Zap, Bijou Funnies, Motor City, Mr. Natural, Yellow Dog and dozens of others. Most of the issues come from the original publisher's file at The Print Mint, a major publisher of underground comics based in the San Francisco Bay Area during the genre's heyday (1968-1974), and the first publisher to focus heavily on the underground comix movement. The collection includes works by Robert Crumb, Victor Moscoso, Rick Griffin, Joel Beck, Vaughn Bode and many others.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Underground comix are small press, underground or self-published comic books which often present alternative or counter cultural viewpoints. Subjects frequently include alternative lifestyles, satirical challenges to middle-class values and mainstream culture, with regular appearances of recreational drug use, nudity, disrespect for authority, rock n' roll, political dissent, or gratuitous sex and violence. These topics resonated with youth culture of the 1960s and 70s, which set itself at odds with mainstream adult America. Several of the titles present in this collection, such as Horseshit, Zap, Snatch, and the SCUM Manifesto, were banned by various local authorities, resulting in the arrests of some publishers and news dealers for publishing pornography.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
A collection of underground comic books and related printed material, spanning from approximately 1948-1978. The collection contains precursors to the genre, including 174 Tiajuana Bibles, individual zines, along with galley proofs and proof books of issues of Zap and Motor City. The collection also features an extensive representation of some of the genre's most celebrated titles such as Zap, Bijou Funnies, Motor City, Mr. Natural, Yellow Dog and dozens of others. Most of the issues come from the original publisher's file at The Print Mint, a major publisher of underground comics based in the San Francisco Bay Area during the genre's heyday (1968-1974), and the first publisher to focus heavily on the underground comix movement. The collection includes works by Robert Crumb, Victor Moscoso, Rick Griffin, Joel Beck, Vaughn Bode and many others.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Hime, Mark.; Beck, Joel.; Bodé, Vaughn, 1941-1975.; Crumb, R.; Griffin, Rick.; Moscoso, Victor.
Subjects:
American wit and humor, Pictorial.; Caricatures and cartoons.; Comic books, strips, etc.; Comic books, strips, etc. -- Political aspects.; Comic books, strips, etc. -- Social aspects.; Counterculture.; Erotic comic books, strips, etc.; Erotic stories, American.; Feminism > Comic books, strips, etc.; Freedom of the press.; Hippies.; Popular culture.; Psychedelic art.; Radicalism.; Social history.; Subculture.; Women
Form and Genre Terms:
Comics (Graphic works).; Underground comics.; Underground press publications.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Series 1: Proofs
Series II. Series 2: Pulp papers
Series III. Series 3: Comics
Series IV. Series 4: Zines
Series V. Series 5: Ephemera
Series VI. Series 6. 50 duplicates from the Print Mind publisher’s file
CONTAINER LIST
- Series 1: Proofs
  - Zap proof Book issue #2, Undated; Moscoso, Victor (Box 1)
    Galley Proof with Photostat pages for Zap #4. Print Mint file copy. Plain brown wrappers with “ZAP” lettered in ink on the upper cover. Camera ready pages pasted in.
  - Zap proof Book issue #3, Undated (Box 1)
    Page Layout Dummy. Original drawings on the upper cover (in pencil) and lower cover (in ink). Original ink by Victor Moscoso. Pages largely blank, presumably awaiting pasted in camera ready artwork, with penciled annotations indicating which panels belong on each page.
  - Galley proofs for Zap issue #2, Undated (Box 1)
  - Galley proofs for Zap issue #3, Undated (Box 1)
  - Black and white proofs Zap issue #3, Undated (Box 1)
  - Black and white proofs Zap issue #3, #4, Undated (Box 1)
  - Proof sheets for Motor City Comics #2, Undated (Box 1)
    Folded (no covers)
  - Zap Proof Sheets, Undated (Mapcase-folder 1)
    38 Proofs in various states of color separation
- Series 2: Pulp papers
  - L.A. Digger News, No. 1, 1967 (Box 2)
    1st edition of underground newspaper
  - Free Student News, Undated (Box 2)
    Berkeley, C.A.
  - Yellow Dog Vol. 1 - Vol 12, 1968-1969 (Box 2)
    10 issues
  - King Bee #1, 1969 (Box 2)
    Front cover art by R. Crumb, contributions by Crumb, S. Clay Wilson, Wes Wilson, Victor Moscoso, and Rick Griffin.
  - Gothic Blimp Works, 1970 (Box 2)
    Issues 1 through 8
  - East Village Other, Vol. 2 No. 24, 1967-11-01-1967-11-15 (Box 2)
    One of the early countercultural newspapers to emerge, frequently featuring comic strips by R. Crumb, Kim Deitch, and others.
  - East Village Other, Vol. 4 No. 13, 1969-03-01 (Box 2)
  - Yarrowstalks no. 3, 1967; Crumb, Robert (Box 2)
  - Jail Bait of the Month, 1969; Crumb, Robert (Mapcase-folder 2)
    Poster which came with Oz Magazine no. 24, published in the UK. On the reverse is a replica of the front page from the UK newspaper The People
- Series 3: Comics
  - Gamut Vol. 1, 1960-06 (Box 16)
  - Cheech Wizard, Undated; Bode, Vaughn (Box 16)
    Heritage Auctions sitcker on the back.
  - Das Kampf, 1963-05 (Box 16)
    1 st edition of the second underground comix, the first with an anti-war theme. 11 copies known. Vaughn Bode's personal copy with final changes and corrections.
  - Foo! Lampoons and Parody Vol. 1 No. 1, 1958-09; Crumb, Robert (Box 16)
  - Note, 1962-04-10 (Box 16)
    First printing from original
  - God Nose, 1964; Jackson, Jack (Box 16)
  - God Nose, 1964; Jackson, Jack (Box 16)
    Signed first edition by Jack Jackson
  - About revolting Lenny of Laredo, 1965; Beck, Joel (Box 16)
    First edition by Joel Beck
  - About revolting Lenny of Laredo, 1965; Beck, Joel (Box 16)
  - About revolting Lenny of Laredo, 1966; Beck, Joel (Box 16)
  - Marching Marvin, Undated; Beck, Joel (Box 16)
  - The Profit, 1966; Beck, Joel (Box 16)
  - The Saint Louis Bug No. 1, 1968; Bode, Vaughn (Box 16)
  - Surfer Toons, Undated (Box 16)
    First printing including original art
  - FYEF, 1967 (Box 16)
    John Mompson 1st edition
  - Wonder Wart-Hog Magazine No. 2, 1967 (Box 16)
  - My Own Mag No. 5 and No. 7, 1964-05 (Box 2)
    William Burroughs, Special Tangier Edition and Moving Times
  - Air Pirates Funnies No. 1, 1971-07; Slabbed comix (Box 3)
  - Cunt Comic No. 1, 1969; Slabbed comix (Box 3)
  - Jiz Comics, 1969; Crumb, Robert; Slabbed comix (Box 3)
  - Motor City Comics No. 1, 1969-04; Slabbed comix (Box 3)
  - Motor City Comics No. 2, 1970-02; Slabbed comix (Box 3)
  - Zap No. 0, 1967-10; Slabbed comix (Box 3)
  - Zap No. 1, 1967-11; Slabbed comix (Box 3)
    3 copies at various grades
  - Zap No. 2, 1968; Slabbed comix (Box 3)
  - Zap No. 5, Undated; Slabbed comix (Box 3)
    Signed by Robert Williams
  - Snatch Comics No. 1, 1968-10; Slabbed comix (Box 3)
  - Snatch Comics No. 3, 1969-08; Slabbed comix (Box 3)
  - Mr. Natural No. 1, 1970-08; Slabbed comix (Box 3)
  - Aardvark papers, Undated (Box 5)
  - Aardvark 2, 1971 (Box 5)
  - Air Pirates Vol 1. No,1, 1971 (Box 5)
  - All Girl Thrills No. 1, 1970 (Box 5)
  - Amazing Dope Tales Vol. 1 No.1, Undated (Box 5)
  - Amazon Comics, 1972 (Box 5)
    2 Copies
  - American Flyer Funnies, 1971 (Box 5)
  - Anomaly, 1972 (Box 5)
  - Archie Issue No.1, Bettiy and Veronica, 1971 (Box 5)
    "Good, clean all-american ssex, pot party, Bar BQ blast"
  - Armadillo Comics Two, 1971 (Box 5)
  - Artistic Comics, 1973 (Box 5)
  - Avenging World, 1973 (Box 5)
  - Barbarian Comics No.1, 1972 (Box 5)
  - Barbarian Comics No.2, 1973 (Box 5)
  - Bent No.1, 1971-04-01 (Box 5)
  - Big Ass Comics No.1, 1969 (Box 5)
    Green shoes and green pants on front cover
  - Big Ass Comics No.1, 1969 (Box 5)
    Brown shoes and green pants on front cover
  - Big Ass Comics No.1, 1971 (Box 5)
    No copyright marks, glossy cover
  - Big Ass Comics No.1, 1969 (Box 5)
  - Big Ass Comics No.2, 1971-08 (Box 5)
  - Big Ass Comics No.2, 1971 (Box 5)
  - Big Ass Comics No.2, 1971 (Box 5)
  - Bijou Funnies Vol. 1 No. 1, 1968 (Box 5)
    1st printing
  - Bijou Funnies Vol. 1 No. 1, 1969 (Box 5)
    2nd printing (two copies)
  - Bijou Funnies Vol. 1 No. 2, 1969 (Box 5)
    1st Printing
  - Bijou Funnies Vol. 1 No. 2, 1972 (Box 5)
    3rd printing
  - Bijou Funnies Vol. 1 No. 3, 1969 (Box 5)
  - Bijou Funnies Vol. 1 No. 3, 1970 (Box 5)
    2nd printing
  - Bijou Funnies Vol. 1 No. 3, 1972 (Box 5)
  - Bijou Funnies Vol. 1 No. 4, 1970 (Box 5)
  - Bijou Funnies Vol. 1 No. 4, 1970 (Box 5)
  - Bijou Funnies Vol. 1 No. 5, 1970 (Box 5)
  - Bijou Funnies Vol. 1 No. 5, 1971 (Box 5)
  - Bijou Funnies Vol. 1 No. 5, 1972 (Box 5)
    4th printing
  - Bijou Funnies Vol. 1 No. 6, 1971 (Box 6)
  - Bijou Funnies Vol. 1 No. 6, 1971 (Box 6)
  - Bijou Funnies Vol. 1 No. 6, 1972 (Box 6)
  - Bijou Funnies Vol. 1 No. 7, 1972 (Box 6)
  - Bijou Funnies Vol. 1 No. 7, 1972 (Box 6)
  - Bijou Funnies Vol. 1 No. 7, 1972 (Box 6)
  - Bijou Funnies Vol. 1 No. 8, 1973 (Box 6)
  - Bijou Funnies Vol. 1 No. 8, 1974 (Box 6)
  - Binky Brown meets the Holy Virgin Mary, 1972 (Box 6)
  - Bizarre Sex Vol. 1 No. 1, 1972 (Box 6)
  - Bizarre Sex Vol. 1 No. 1, 1977 (Box 6)
    5th printing
  - Bizarre Sex Vol. 1 No. 2, 1972-11 (Box 6)
  - Bizarre Sex Vol. 1 No. 2, 1977-09 (Box 6)
    2nd revised printing
  - Bizarre Sex Vol. 1 No. 3, 1973-06 (Box 6)
  - Bizarre Sex Vol. 1 No. 4, 1975-10 (Box 6)
  - Black and White Comics, 1973-06 (Box 6)
  - Black and White Comics, 1973-06 (Box 6)
  - Bogeyman Comics No.1, 1969 (Box 6)
  - Bogeyman Comics No.2, 1969 (Box 6)
  - Bogeyman Comics No.3, 1970 (Box 6)
  - Brain Fantasy, 1972 (Box 6)
  - Can't Bust'Em, 1971 (Box 6)
  - Buy This Book of Odd Bodkins, 1965 (Box 6)
  - The Captain, 1972 (Box 6)
  - Captains Guts No.1, 1969 (Box 6)
    White shirt and tights
  - Captains Guts No.2, 1969 (Box 6)
  - Captains Guts No.3, 1971 (Box 6)
  - Cheech Wizard/Schizophrenia, 1973 (Box 6)
  - The Collected Cheech Wizard, 1972 (Box 6)
  - The Collected Cheech Wizard, 1972 (Box 6)
  - Choice Neats Comics Vol. 1 No. 1, 1971 (Box 6)
  - Cloud Comix No.1, 1971 (Box 7)
  - Color, 1971 (Box 7)
  - Dan O'Neil's Comics, 1948-01 (Box 7)
    1st issue with red ink on inside covers
  - Commies from Mars, 1973-03 (Box 7)
  - Conspiracy Capers No. 1, 1969 (Box 7)
  - Coochy Cooty Men's Comics, 1970 (Box 7)
  - R. Crumb's Comics and Stories No. 1, 1964-04 (Box 7)
  - Damsel in Distress, 007 James Bone, Undated (Box 7)
  - Up from the Deep No. 1 (Box 7)
  - Deep 3D Comix Vol. 1 No. 1, 1970 (Box 7)
  - Despair, Undated (Box 7)
    Plunge into the depths of..
  - Deviant Slice No.1, 1972 (Box 7)
  - Deviant Slice No.1, 1972 (Box 7)
  - Deviant Slice No.2, 1973 (Box 7)
  - Dillo Toons, 1969 (Box 7)
  - The Dirty Duck, 1972 (Box 7)
  - Dirty Laudry Comics, 1974 (Box 7)
  - The Dying Dolphin, Undated (Box 7)
  - Ebon Vol. 1 No. 1, 1970-01 (Box 7)
  - El Perfecto Comics, 1973 (Box 7)
  - Fantagor No. 1, 1970 (Box 7)
  - Fantagor No. 2, 1972 (Box 7)
  - Fantagor No. 3, 1972 (Box 7)
  - Fantagor No. 4, 1972 (Box 7)
  - Fat Lip Funnies, 1969 (Box 7)
  - Feds N Heads, 1968 (Box 7)
  - Feds N Heads, 1969 (Box 7)
  - Feel Good Funnies, 1972 (Box 7)
  - Fever Dreams No. 1, 1972-07 (Box 7)
  - Four-Star Finale, 1970 (Box 7)
  - Ruby the Dike Visits Some Friends, 1970 (Box 7)
  - The Collected Freak Brothers, 1971 (Box 7)
  - Further Adventures of Those Fabulous Furry Freak Brothers, 1972 (Box 7)
  - Funny Animals, 1972 (Box 7)
  - Gas Comics, 1970 (Box 7)
  - God Nose, Undated (Box 7)
  - God Nose, 1971 (Box 7)
    4th Printing
  - Good Jives Comix No. 1, 1972 (Box 8)
  - Good Jives Comix No. 2, 1973 (Box 8)
  - Greaser Comics No. 1, 1971 (Box 8)
  - Googiewaumer Comics No. 2.5, 1969 (Box 8)
  - Grim Wit No. 2, 1973 (Box 8)
  - Happu Ending Comics, 1969 (Box 8)
  - Heavy Tragi-Comics, 1969 (Box 8)
  - Heehee, 1970 (Box 8)
  - Home Grown Funnies, 1971-01 (Box 8)
  - Home Grown Funnies, 1971-05 (Box 8)
  - Honky Tonk, 1970 (Box 8)
  - Hungry Chuck Biscuits Comics and Stories Vo. 1 No. 1, 1971-11 (Box 8)
  - Hydrogen Bomb and Biochemical Warfare Funnies, 1970 (Box 8)
  - Your Hytone Comix, 1971-02 (Box 8)
  - If the Shoe Fits No. 2, 1971 (Box 8)
  - Illuminations, 1971 (Box 8)
  - The Image of the Beast, 1973 (Box 8)
  - Insect Fear No. 1, 1970 (Box 8)
  - Insect Fear No. 2, 1970 (Box 8)
  - Insect Fear No. 3, 1972 (Box 8)
  - It Ain't Me Babe, 1970-07 (Box 8)
  - It Ain't Me Babe, 1970-07 (Box 8)
  - Jesus Meets the Armed Services, 1970 (Box 8)
  - Jiz Comics, 1972 (Box 8)
  - Junk Comix, Undated (Box 8)
  - Junkwaffel No.1, 1971; Bode, Vaughn (Box 8)
  - Junkwaffel No.2, 1972; Bode, Vaughn (Box 8)
  - Junkwaffel No.3, 1972; Bode, Vaughn (Box 8)
  - Junkwaffel No.4, 1972; Bode, Vaughn (Box 8)
  - The Kingdom of Heaven is Within You Comix, 1969 (Box 8)
  - Koan Comics, 1969 (Box 8)
  - Radical America Komiks Vol. 3 No. 1, 1969 (Box 8)
  - Kuk λωψ No. 1, 1969 (Box 9)
  - Laugh in the Dark, 1971 (Box 9)
  - Laugh in the Dark, 1971 (Box 9)
  - Lean Years, 1974 (Box 9)
  - The Life and Loves of Cleopatra, 1969 (Box 9)
  - Light, 1971 (Box 9)
  - The Man, 1972; Bode, Vaughn (Box 9)
  - The Machines, 1967; Bode, Vaughn (Box 9)
  - Manhunt, 1973 (Box 9)
  - Mom's Homemade Comics Vol. 1 No. 1, 1969 (Box 9)
  - Mom's Homemade Comics Vol. 1 No. 1, 1969 (Box 9)
  - Mom's Homemade Comics Vol. 1 No. 2, 1970 (Box 9)
  - Mom's Homemade Comics Vol. 1 No. 3, 1971-02 (Box 9)
  - Mondo Snarfo, 1978 (Box 9)
  - Monolith, 1972 (Box 9)
  - Moonchild Comics No. 1, 1968 (Box 9)
  - Moonchild Comics No. 2, 1969 (Box 9)
  - Moondog, 1969 (Box 9)
  - Merton of the Movement, 1972 (Box 9)
  - Mickey Rat Comix No. 2, 1972 (Box 9)
  - Mother's Oats Comix, 1969-10 (Box 9)
  - Mother's Oats Comix, 1969-10 (Box 9)
  - Motor City Comics No. 1, 1969-04 (Box 9)
  - Motor City Comics No. 1, 1969 (Box 9)
  - Motor City Comics No. 1, 1969 (Box 9)
    4th edition
  - Motor City Comics No. 2, 1970 (Box 9)
  - Motor City Comics No. 2, 1970 (Box 9)
    3rd edition
  - Mr. Natural No.1, 1971 (Box 9)
  - Mr. Natural No.1, 1971 (Box 9)
  - Mr. Natural No.2, 1971 (Box 9)
  - My Big Banana, Undated (Box 9)
  - Nard N' Pat Vol. 1 No. 1, 1974 (Box 9)
  - The New Adventures of Jesus, 1969 (Box 9)
  - The New Adventures of Jesus, 1971 (Box 9)
  - Noof Unnies No. 1, 1970 (Box 10)
  - Tales from the Ozone No. 1, 1969 (Box 10)
  - Tales from the Ozone No. 2, 1970 (Box 10)
  - The People's Comics, 1972 (Box 10)
  - Don Dohler's Projunior, 1971 (Box 10)
  - Don Dohler's Projunior, 1973 (Box 10)
  - Pulp Comics No. 1, 1971-01 (Box 10)
  - Pulp Comics No. 1, 1971-01 (Box 10)
  - Pulp Comics No. 2, 1973 (Box 10)
  - Psychotic Adventures Illustrated No. 1, 1972 (Box 10)
  - Psychotic Adventures Illustrated No. 2, 1973 (Box 10)
  - Psychotic Adventures Illustrated No. 3, 1972 (Box 10)
  - Red Raider, 1977 (Box 10)
  - Ric Sloane Comics No.1, 1969 (Box 10)
  - It's Only Rock and Roll Comix, 1975 (Box 10)
  - Rowlf, 1971 (Box 10)
  - Roxy Funnies Vol. 1 No. 1, 1972 (Box 10)
  - Rubber Duck No.1, 1971 (Box 10)
  - Rubber Duck No.2, 1972 (Box 10)
  - San Francisco Comic Book Vol. 1 No. 1, 1970-01 (Box 10)
    3 copies
  - San Francisco Comic Book Vol. 1 No. 3, 1970 (Box 10)
  - Teen-age Horizons of Shangrila Vol. 1 No. 1, 1970 (Box 10)
  - Teen-age Horizons of Shangrila Vol. 1 No. 2, 1972 (Box 10)
  - Short Order Comix, 1973 (Box 10)
  - Show and Tell Comics, 1973 (Box 10)
  - The Irresistable Silver Screen, 1970 (Box 10)
  - Skull Comics Vol. 1 No. 1, 1970 (Box 10)
  - Skull Comics Vol. 1 No. 2, 1970 (Box 10)
  - Skull Comics Vol. 1 No. 3, 1971 (Box 10)
  - Skull Comics Vol. 1 No. 4, 1972 (Box 10)
  - Skull Comics Vol. 1 No. 5, 1972 (Box 10)
  - Skull Comics Vol. 1 No. 6, 1972 (Box 10)
  - Sleazy Scandals of the Silver Screen, 1974 (Box 11)
  - Slow Death Funnies No. 1, 1970 (Box 11)
  - Slow Death Funnies No. 2, 1970 (Box 11)
  - Slow Death Funnies No. 3, 1971 (Box 11)
  - Slow Death Funnies No. 4, 1972 (Box 11)
  - Slow Death Funnies No. 5, 1973 (Box 11)
  - Slow Death Funnies No. 6, 1974 (Box 11)
  - Smile Vol. 1 No. 1, 1970 (Box 11)
  - Snare No. 1, 1972 (Box 11)
  - Snare No. 2, 1972 (Box 11)
  - Snare No. 3, 1972 (Box 11)
  - Snare No. 4, 1973 (Box 11)
  - Snatch No. 1, 1968 (Box 11)
  - Snatch No. 1, 1968 (Box 11)
  - Snatch No. 2, 1969-01 (Box 11)
  - Snatch No. 3, 1969 (Box 11)
  - Snatch No. 3, 1969 (Box 11)
  - Softcore, 1973 (Box 11)
  - Spaced Out, 1972 (Box 11)
  - Spare, Undated (Box 11)
  - Spasm, 1973 (Box 11)
  - Spiffy, 1969 (Box 11)
  - The Spirit Vol. 1 No. 1, 1973-01 (Box 11)
  - Star Reach, 1974 (Box 11)
  - Subvert No. 1, 1970 (Box 11)
  - Subvert No. 2, 1972 (Box 11)
  - Sunpot with Blueprint Poster, 1971 (Box 11)
  - Suds, 1969 (Box 11)
  - Tuff Shit, 1972 (Box 11)
  - Tales from the Plague, 1971 (Box 11)
  - Tales of Toad and Other Stories No. 1, 1970 (Box 11)
  - Tales of Toad and Other Stories No. 2, 1971 (Box 11)
  - Tales of Toad and Other Stories No. 3, 1973 (Box 11)
  - Tales from the Tube No. 1, 1973 (Box 12)
  - Tasty, 1970 (Box 12)
  - Tasty Comix, 1969 (Box 12)
  - Terminal comics, 1971 (Box 12)
  - Thrilling Murder, 1971 (Box 12)
  - Tiajuana Bible Revival, Undated (Box 12)
  - The Tortoise and the Hare, 1971 (Box 12)
  - Truckin' No. 1, 1972 (Box 12)
  - Truckin' No. 2, 1974 (Box 12)
  - Uncle Sham, 1970 (Box 12)
  - Uneeda Comix, 1970 (Box 12)
  - Weird Fantasies No. 1, 1972 (Box 12)
  - Weirdom Comix No. 14, 1971-07 (Box 12)
  - Weirdom Comix No. 15, 1972-05 (Box 12)
  - Wimmen's Comix No. 1, 1972 (Box 12)
  - Wimmen's Comix No. 2, 1973 (Box 12)
  - Wimmen's Comix No. 3, 1973 (Box 12)
  - Wonder Wart-Hog Vol. 1, Spring (Box 12)
  - XYZ Comics, 1972 (Box 12)
  - Yellow Dog Comics Vol. 2 No. 3 Issue 13, 1969 (Box 12)
  - Yellow Dog Comics Vol. 2 No. 3 Issue 15, 1969 (Box 12)
  - Yellow Dog Comics Vol. 2 No. 3 Issue 16, 1969 (Box 12)
  - Yellow Dog Comics Vol. 2 No. 3 Issue 17, 1970 (Box 12)
  - Yellow Dog Comics Vol. 2 No. 3 Issue 18, 1970 (Box 12)
  - Yellow Dog Comics Vol. 2 No. 3 Issue 19, 1970 (Box 12)
  - Yellow Dog Comics Vol. 2 No. 3 Issue 20, 1971 (Box 12)
  - Yellow Dog Comics Vol. 2 No. 3 Issue 21, 1971 (Box 12)
  - Yellow Dog Comics Vol. 2 No. 3 Issue 22, 1972 (Box 12)
  - Young Lust No. 1, 1970 (Box 12)
    1st printing 2 copies
  - Young Lust No. 2, 1971 (Box 12)
  - Young Lust No. 3, 1972 (Box 12)
  - Zap Comix No. 0, 1967 (Box 13)
    2nd printing 2 copies
  - Zap Comix No.1, 1967-11 (Box 13)
  - Zap Comix No.1, 1967 (Box 13)
    3rd printing 2 copies
  - Zap Comix No. 2, 1968 (Box 13)
  - Zap Comix No. 3, 1968 (Box 13)
  - Zap Comix No. 4, 1969 (Box 13)
  - Zap Comix No. 5, 1969 (Box 13)
  - Zap Comix No. 6, 1970 (Box 13)
- Series 4: Zines
  - Fritz the Cat, 1968; Crumb, Robert (Box 2)
  - Air Pirates Funnies Vol. 1, No.1, 1972 (Box 4)
  - Allstars comic book, 1970 (Box 4)
    Contributions by Greg Irons, Rick Griffin, Moscoso, et al.
  - Baloney Moccasins Issue 1, Undated (Box 4)
  - The Big Yellow Drawing Book, 1974 (Box 4)
  - Changes No. 3, 1969 (Box 4)
    Includes R. Crumb cartoon on interior of rear cover.
  - Chicago Mirror Vol. 1, No. 1, No.2, Autumn to Winter (Box 4)
  - Dead Flowers, 1968; Tomson, John (Box 4)
  - Eureka, 1968 (Box 4)
  - Horseshit No. 1, 1965 (Box 4)
  - Horseshit No. 2, 1967 (Box 4)
  - Horseshit No. 3, 1968 (Box 4)
    In 1968, Horseshit was responsible (along with Zap, Snatch, and the SCUM Manifesto) for the arrest of Berkeley bookseller Moe Moskowitz on charges of selling pornography
  - Horseshit No. 4, 1969 (Box 4)
  - The New Gravity, 1970 (Box 4)
  - Plague No. 1, 1960 (Box 4)
  - Prairie State Blues, 1970 (Box 4)
    Comic strips and graphic tales by Bill Bergeron
  - The softcore pornographic coloring book, 1971; Beck, Joel (Box 4)
  - Thunderhead Photo Phantasies, 1971 (Box 4)
  - Promethean Enterprises, 1969 (Box 4)
    Includes work by R. Crumb
- Series 5: Ephemera
  - R. Crumb's Headcomix Sticker, Undated (Box 2)
  - Approximately 174 Tijuana Bibles, Undated (Box 16)
  - Complete Set of Topps Bubble-Gum cards, 1965; Crumb, Robert (Box 16)
  - 2 Berkeley Con Pins, 1973 (Box 16)
  - Biju Funnies Iron-on T-Shirt Transfers, 1970 (Box 16)
  - Underground comix order slip, Undated (Box 16)
  - Berkeley Con program book, 1973 (Box 16)
  - Radical America Poetry and Comix, 1968-09-1968-10 (Box 16)
  - The Yum Yum book, 1975; Crumb, Robert (Box 16)
- Series 6. 50 duplicates from the Print Mind publisher’s file
  - American Flyer Funnies No. 1, 1971 (Box 14)
  - Barbarian Comics No. 1, 1973 (Box 14)
  - The Book of Raziel No. 1, 1969 (Box 14)
  - Can’t Bust 'Em No. 1, 1971 (Box 14)
  - The Captain No. 1, 1972 (Box 14)
  - Captain Guts No.1, 1969 (Box 14)
  - Gaptain Guts No.3, 1971 (Box 14)
  - Coochy Cooty Men’s Comics No.1, 1970 (Box 14)
  - Deviant Slice No.1, 1972 (Box 14)
  - Deviant Slice No.2, 1973 (Box 14)
  - Good Jive No. 1, 1972 (Box 14)
  - Good Jive No. 2, 1973 (Box 14)
  - Googiewaumer Comics No. 1, 1969 (Box 14)
    2 Copies, 1st printing
  - Heavy Comics No.1, 1969 (Box 14)
  - Illuminations No.1, 1971 (Box 14)
  - It Ain't Me Babe, 1970 (Box 14)
  - Junkwaffel No. 2, 1972 (Box 14)
  - Junkwaffel No. 4, 1972 (Box 14)
  - The Kingdom of Heaven is Within You Comix No.1, 1969 (Box 14)
  - Kuk λωψ No. 1, 1969 (Box 14)
  - Lean Years, 1974 (Box 14)
  - Light No.1, 1971 (Box 14)
  - Manhunt, 1972 (Box 14)
  - Marching Marvin The Red Watcher. No.1, Undated (Box 14)
  - Moonchild Comics No.2, 1969 (Box 14)
  - The Profit, 1966 (Box 14)
  - Pulp Comics No. 1, 1971 (Box 15)
    3 copies, 1st printing
  - Pulp Comics No. 2, 1973 (Box 15)
  - Psychotic Adventures Illustrated No. 1, 1972 (Box 15)
  - R. Crumb’s Comics and Stories, 1969 (Box 15)
  - Rubber Duck No. 1, 1971 (Box 15)
  - Rubber Duck No. 2, 1972 (Box 15)
  - Show and Tell Comics No. 1, 1973 (Box 15)
  - Slow Death Funnies No.1, 1970 (Box 15)
  - Softcore No.1, 1973 (Box 15)
  - Spaced Out No. 1, 1972 (Box 15)
  - Spiffy Stories No.1, 1969 (Box 15)
  - Suds No. 1, 1969 (Box 15)
  - Tales of the Toad No. 2, 1969 (Box 15)
  - Truckin' No. 1, 1974 (Box 15)
  - Uncle Sham No. 1, 1970 (Box 15)
  - Zap Comics No. 6, 1973 (Box 15)